Email: softluster4753@gmail.com Mobile: +82-10-3023-6720

### Summary

An all-around player with extensive experience in various fields. Expert in web server back-end development, particularly in the billing domain, but also proficient as a web front-end developer using React with JSX or TypeScript. Recently completed a full-time master's degree in natural language processing, fully funded with preferential treatment from Samsung Electronics. Previously developed bootloader and device driver as a system engineer in the BSP team.

### Programming Skills

- Languages: Java, SQL, Shell script, Terraform HCL, Javascript (+ JSX, Typescript), HTML/CSS, Python, C/C++
- Tools: Spring (MVC, WebFlux, JPA, Security), AWS, Docker, SoapUI, MySQL, React, PyTorch, HuggingFace
- Others: RESTful API, HTTP, TLS, Oauth 2.0, OOP/OOAD/DDD, Clean coding, TDD, Agile development (XP & Scrum), PCI-DSS (+ 3DS2), Device driver, Jira/Confluence, Git/SVN

#### EXPERIENCE

## TV Plus development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Staff Engineer

Mar 2024 - Present

- Led CMS development (2024 Present)
- SRL methodology development Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Researcher

June 2022 - Feb 2024

• Analyze and develop efficient methodologies for learning high-quality sentence representations based on large-scale language models: Used PyTorch, HuggingFace

## Billing development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Engineer

Nov 2016 - March 2022

- o Led CP portal redevelopment: Used React, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA (2020 2022)
- Developed DSA agreement (2021)
- Developed subscription product change for active subscription (2021)
- o Implemented 3DS2 respond to EU PSD2 law regulations (2020)
- $\circ~$  Developed remote login to Samsung Smart TV using smartphone (2020)
- Developed integration test framework: Used SoapUI, Groovy (2019)
- o Migrate buyer portal from monolithic to MSA: Used AWS ECS, Terraform HCL (2019)
- Led buyer portal redevelopment: Used React, Spring Boot, JPA (2018)

## BSP development — Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.

Suwon, Korea

Engineer

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016

- Port ramdump feature to Samsung Smart TV Kernel (2016)
  - Contributed to kexec-tools utility (https://bit.ly/3yG44df)

#### EDUCATION

#### Hanyang University

Seoul, Korea

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.06/4.5

Mar 2022 - Feb 2024

#### Hongik University

Seoul, Korea

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering; GPA: 3.5/4.5

Mar 2008 - Feb 2015

### **PUBLICATIONS**

• Young Hyun Yoo, Kyumin Lee, Minjin Jeon, Jii Cha, Kangsan Kim, and Taeuk Kim, Comparison and Analysis of Unsupervised Contrastive Learning Approaches for Korean Sentence Representations, *The 34th Annual Conference on Human and Cognitive Language Technology* (HCLT 2022).

# Additional information

- Languages: English (professional working proficiency), Korean (native)
- $\bullet$  Achievements: Excellent S/W Developer Award (2022, every half year,  ${\sim}500$  employees)

(Last update: 22/Feb/2024)